Shay Nezaki

Vancouver, BC, Canada | (+1) 778-980-9578 | s.nezaki@outlook.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio

SUMMARY

I love to transform numbers into strategy. With over 3 years of experience collecting, cleaning, analyzing, and visualizing data in the financial and educational industries, I have a track record of delivering meaningful insights and driving efficiencies. I'm now seeking a role to step up my career in business intelligence and data analytics.

Skills: SQL, R, Power BI, Microsoft Access, Excel, Google Sheets, BigQuery, Tableau **Languages:** English, Japanese

WORK EXPERIENCE

Marketing Assistant

March 2023 - Present

VanWest College - Vancouver, British Columbia

- Improved the Google Sheet for student information by adding or changing formulas based on team requests, which decreased the time for data entry by 20% while increasing the accuracy of data
- Verified completeness and accuracy of 500+ student applications per year, ensuring compliance with school policies and regulatory requirements
- Liaised between education agents, the admission team, and other relevant departments to provide timely and accurate information for efficient collaboration; responding to inquiries within 24 hours and keeping agents informed of commission rates and promotions

Program Coordinator / Program Assistant VanWest College - Vancouver, British Columbia

May 2022 - March 2023

- Developed, maintained, and adapted Vocational College Program course schedules to respond to the changing numbers and needs of the college; provided timely and effective solutions in coordination with the Academic Director
- Maintained discretion regarding academic information, current privacy laws, and professional practices between instructors, students, and advisors, as well as other departments in the college
- Coordinated with the Academic Director to communicate academic policies to 1000+ students and responded to policy change inquiries as needed

Research Assistant

September 2021 - May 2022

Langara College - Vancouver, British Columbia

Research project: Immigration Education and Employment Pathways for International Students in BC

- Transcribed 20+ interviews with international students about their experiences in Canada to understand their challenges and struggles
- Carried out research into TikTok and YouTube videos posted by international students such as categorizing videos and compiling data on the locations and number of views

Shay Nezaki

Vancouver, BC, Canada | (+1) 778-980-9578 | s.nezaki@outlook.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio

Marketing Coordinator

October 2017 - April 2019

Rakuten Bank - Tokyo, Japan

- Launched new promotions after analyzing the timing and value of personal loans using Microsoft Access, which led to a 15% increase in customer borrowing
- Analyzed the number of outbound calls in which call center agents succeeded in providing loans to customers and increased the number of successful calls by 20% compared to before the data was organized using Microsoft Excel and Access
- Re-engaged customers by sending direct mail to those who could not be reached by email
 or phone, which led to a 5% year-on-year increase in the number of customers who took
 out loans

Customer Service Supervisor

June 2016 - September 2017

Rakuten Bank - Tokyo, Japan

- Mentored 40 call center agents, managed escalations, took over serious complaints, and held monthly meetings to give feedback, which resulted in less than 10% of the turnover rate in a year
- Handled approximately 40 phone calls from customers per day and offered solutions, which kept the abandon rate less than 4%

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Immigrant Advisory Table Member

March 2022 - August 2023

Vancouver Local Immigration Partnership - Vancouver, British Columbia

 Supported VLIP research initiatives and provided information and expertise on local immigration trends and needs of the community

Human Resources Assistant

July 2021 - August 2022

Canadian Red Cross - Ottawa, Ontario

- Reviewed resumes and screened applicants who applied to emergency responder roles
- Collaborated with other HR assistants and the HR coordinator to track applicants and achieve department KPIs, such as response time to application using Taleo and Smartsheet

EDUCATION & TRAINING

Google Data Analytics Professional CertificateIssued in December 2023BrainStation Data Analytics CertificateIssued in September 2021

Business Administration, Post-Degree Diploma

May 2020 - April 2022

Langara College, Vancouver, British Columbia

Bachelor of Laws, Administrative Law

April 2012 - March 2016

Waseda University, Tokyo, Japan